berkleemusic.com 2016-12-03

# Berklee Online - Music Degree, Certificates, Courses

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully before using online.berklee.edu ("Web site"), an Internet site maintained by Berklee College of Music, Inc. ("Berklee"). Your use of the Web site serves as your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and consent to Berklee's collection and use of the information you provide as set forth in the Privacy Policy. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to the Web site, and not to other Web sites operated by other companies or organizations to which we may link. When you link to any other Web sites from the Web site, this policy no longer applies and Berklee has no control of the activities of those Web sites. Also this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that Berklee may collect from you in any manner other than online. 

Berklee may revise this Privacy Policy at any time. You should, therefore, review it periodically. If you do not want to submit personal information when requested, you will not be able to access certain areas on our site. However, you do not need to provide personal information to Berklee in order to use the Web site.

### Collection of Information

Berklee generally only collects personally identifiable information from you when you voluntarily submit it to us when you: register with us; enroll in online classes; purchase products from any online stores we offer; participate in contests, events or promotions; send us questions or comments via e-mail; and/or, fill out online surveys, or any other requests we make for suggestions or comments about the Web site. This information may include personal information such as your name, e-mail address, telephone number, and home address. Also, we may request certain demographic information such as your age, and gender. We never collect more information than what is reasonably necessary to fulfill your requests and our legitimate business objectives. We will take appropriate steps to ensure the security and integrity of any information you provide to us.

**If you are under the age of 13, your parent or guardian's consent is required before you can provide any personal information to us for purposes of registration and/or other online activities.**

If we ask you to register with the Web site, we may ask for personal information such as your full name and e-mail address, and mailing address. Berklee may use such information to periodically contact you with news, and relevant announcements. Shoppers purchasing goods and services through our online store must provide a valid credit card number and expiration date, in addition to name, mailing address, phone number and e-mail address. Berklee may sponsor sweepstakes, contests or other events ("Promotions") which require the collection, processing, and storage of individual contact information plus demographic information. If you want to join in on our Promotions, we may ask you to provide an e-mail address, so that we can let you know if you won a prize. For other Berklee promotions, we may request your name and home address in order to send you products or information by regular mail. By allowing you to send email to us, we are not attempting to collect any personal information about you. We will only use personal information (such as name, mailing address and e-mail address) contained in your e-mail to respond to your specific inquiry or comments in the e-mail. Although we may retain your e-mail for a period of time, we will not use any personal information contained in your e-mail for any purpose other than responding to your specific inquiry or comments. 

### How Information is Used

Berklee collects the personal information you provide on the Web site. We may use the information you submit to the Web site to send you advertising or promotional materials, including information about new contests, features and enhancements, special offers and other events of interest. We also use your personal information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve the products and services we provide you and can better meet your needs.

The demographic information (such as age and gender) you provide us is collected by Berklee and may be disclosed in aggregate to third parties. This aggregate demographic information cannot be used to personally identify you or your computer.

### How Berklee Shares Personal Information

From time to time, Berklee may use and share Web site user's personal information with entities who use it solely to provide support for the internal operations of the Web site (for example, online product fulfillment, e-mail services, or technical support). These entities will not use your personal information for any other purpose, and have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the personal information they obtain from us.

We may disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are required to do so by law, including but not limited to disclosure to law enforcement or other government officials in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose you or us to legal liability.

Generally, Berklee only uses personal information collected from and about its users for the purpose for which it is submitted, unless we disclose other uses at the time we collect the information. If we do, you will have the opportunity to instruct us not to use your data in other ways (you can "opt-out" – see below). We may sometimes share personally identifiable information with our affiliates or business partners who might like to send you information about their products or services. If you do not want your information used in this manner, you may "opt-out." We sometimes offer Promotions in conjunction with a sponsor, and may share your information with these sponsors. We will identify the sponsor for you, and provide you with the opportunity to "opt-out." In the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy, or other similar event, Berklee's customer information may be transferred to Berklee's successor or assign, if permitted by and done in accordance with applicable law.

### Information Sharing with Non-Affiliated Third Parties

Because Berklee Online values all customer relationships, it will not disclose customers' nonpublic personal information to nonaffiliated third parties, except as described in this policy or as otherwise permitted by law. We DO NOT allow any email harvesting. If you feel you have been contacted in error by a party other than Berklee Online, please contact Student Support at [ support@online.berklee.edu. ](mailto:support@online.berklee.edu)

### Cookies and IP Addresses

Like most Web sites, Berklee uses "cookies" on the Web site. Cookies are pieces of information that we place on your computer to help us accurately understand how many consumers are visiting a particular site, how often they visit that site, and what content they are most interested in. For example, a cookie will allow us to remember certain things based on your Internet Protocol or "IP" address (an IP address is the string of numbers that identifies each sender or receiver of information that is sent across the Internet), such as the time and duration of your visits, how you navigated through our content and where you exited a particular site. This lets us know how many people are coming to individual sites, how frequently, and how they are using the sites, allowing us to make updates to content and improve navigation as appropriate. We cannot tell who you are or where you are. Berklee will never use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that Berklee did not originally send in a cookie.

### Linking/Co-Branding

To provide relevant information not found on the Web site and to provide a greater variety of online opportunities, Berklee may provide links from the Web site to third party web sites. We encourage our Web site visitors to read third party sites' privacy policies before submitting personal information. Berklee is not responsible for any information these web sites may obtain from you and we do not review or oversee their privacy policies or procedures.

### Opt-Out

If you do not want Berklee to send you e-mail or regular mail about our products and/or services, you can opt-out at the time we collect the information. If you are receiving e-mails or regular mail and at a later date you choose to opt-out and have your name removed from Berklee's e-mailing list, you can do so by using the link included with a Berklee e-mail or by sending an e-mail to [ support@online.berklee.edu. ](mailto:support@online.berklee.edu) Berklee Online will occasionally send email announcing changes or enhancements to our site or services. If you do not wish to receive these announcements, please notify [ support@online.berklee.edu ](mailto:support@online.berklee.edu) that you wish to opt-out of all announcements. 

Students enrolled in a course or program with Berklee Online must be opted in to receive all email communications. Most communication between Berklee Online and it's student body is conducted in this manner.

The various emails keep students up to date on: 

  * *Changes to existing courses and programs
  * *New courses and programs
  * *Special deals and offers from our industry partners only offered to our students!
  * *Other important announcements

In order to ensure all students are kept up to date on the happenings of the online school, we need to be able to communicate through email.

### Reviewing and Changing Personal Information

You may at any time review and/or update the contact information we have for you or inform us that you want us to remove such information from our database by contacting us at [support@online.berklee.edu.](mailto:support@online.berklee.edu)

You must provide us with information on the activities you participated in which requested personal information. Before we can change or delete any information, we require that you provide us with proof of your name and address. Once we receive such proof, we will immediately delete or modify your information and refrain from collecting any other personally identifiable information from you, if you request. Please note, however, that there may be some residual information that may remain in our databases that may or may not contain personally identifiable information. We will not provide this information to any third party, or use it for any commercial purpose.

### Children Under 13

Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), Berklee does not solicit personal information from children. Visitors 13 years of age and under should remember that they are required to obtain an adult's permission before submitting any personal information to this, or any other, Web site.

### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact [support@online.berklee.edu](mailto:support@online.berklee.edu) or by mail:   
Berklee Media   
Berklee College of Music   
1140 Boylston Street   
MS 855   
Boston, MA 02215-3693
